<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Rob Knight</title>
<subtitle type="text">This is where I play.</subtitle>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000" />
<updated>2013-08-21T12:34:46-07:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:4000/</id>
<author>
  <name>Rob Knight</name>
  <uri>http://localhost:4000/</uri>
  <email>hello@robknight.net</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keep moving]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2013/08/keep-moving" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/08/keep-moving</id>
  <published>2013-08-14T23:22:51-07:00</published>
  <updated>2013-08-14T23:22:51-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Rob Knight</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>hello@robknight.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In my 20’s, I never had any doubt about my physical ability. So a simple workout consisting of weight-lifting and some form of cardio (usually a run) was all I needed to keep fit. As much as I love to get exercise, back then it was almost an afterthought. I could roll into the gym on 5 hours sleep and power through a workout and then go for a 3 mile run and not even think about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I approach 40, I think very differently about my overall health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m mortal. I get aches and pains. There is less “bouncing back” and more thud. I routinely get more aches and pains than I did a decade ago. And even though that should be obvious to anyone–including me–the only thing it reminds me of is the need to keep moving. And now that I’m so keenly aware of my own mortality, I feel this ache in my heart to keep myself healthy all the way to the end, whenever that may be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a great bumper sticker quote: “Live hard. Die young. And have a good-looking corpse.” Fuck that. Live well, die old, and be able to stand on your own two feet, right to your very last day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so now I workout truly without taking it for granted. This is my religion. This is my wellness. I do this to prove to myself that I’m living well and not just living. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here I am. At a fresh 37, gracefully trying to maintain a gift I was given at a very young age. The gift of good health.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2013/08/keep-moving&quot;&gt;Keep moving&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Rob Knight at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Rob Knight&lt;/a&gt; on August 14, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The lives of others]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2013/01/the-lives-of-others" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2013/01/the-lives-of-others</id>
  <published>2013-01-11T09:28:01-08:00</published>
  <updated>2013-01-11T09:28:01-08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Rob Knight</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>hello@robknight.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I walked into the office this morning, I noticed a homeless guy hanging out over by Derby Park. The thought of him spending the night in the cold was unbearable to me. I was getting out of a warm car, headed for a (mostly) warm office, to spend the day with warm people. And here was this guy, sitting at a cold metal picnic table on a cold winter morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went in and put my stuff down and decided to go buy him a cup of coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s younger than I am. Through our brief conversation, I learn that he’s an alcoholic who has lived on the street for 7 years. He drinks a beer for breakfast and spends the day collecting recyclables to pay for food and his drinking habit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is his life. He is younger than I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, I think we are afraid to get close to people like him because it reminds us how close we all are to that. Or so we can pretend &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; part of society doesn’t exist: the part that sleeps outside every night for 7 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m now in my warm office, drinking a warm cup of tea, talking to warm people. And he is outside, thinking about a beer, trying to make it all go away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I’m being vague in this writing because I don’t want to think about it. I just want to imagine it doesn’t happen. I just want to pretend the worst of society is boring meetings and uncleaned lunch dishes in the office kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not. Be sympathetic to that. Always be sympathetic to that.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2013/01/the-lives-of-others&quot;&gt;The lives of others&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Rob Knight at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Rob Knight&lt;/a&gt; on January 11, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A candidate's vision]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2012/10/vision" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2012/10/vision</id>
  <published>2012-10-23T07:58:39-07:00</published>
  <updated>2012-10-23T07:58:39-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Rob Knight</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>hello@robknight.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The other day, I was talking with my dad about the election. I told him that my basic decision-making principle came down to each candidate’s vision for the country. If Mitt Romney or Barack Obama were elected tomorrow, and faced no obstacles in shaping the laws of this country to their vision of what is best, which America would I prefer to live in?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without missing a beat, my dad’s response was, “Well, they each need to tell us their &lt;em&gt;plan&lt;/em&gt;, plain and simple.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except, I don’t want to hear about plans. A plan is something you have before reality sets in. A plan is hopefully well-thought, but essentially untested. A plan is what you start with, but rarely looks the same when you are finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to understand each candidate’s &lt;em&gt;vision&lt;/em&gt;. A vision is what guides &lt;strong&gt;every&lt;/strong&gt; decision, including the decision to change plans. A plan is easily reduced to convenient and/or confusing sound bites. But a vision emerges over the course of months and years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are asking for a plan, I believe you’re thinking too short-term. Take a look at both candidates and think about &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; you’ve heard them say over the last year. Think about the things they’ve said before that. Think about the company they keep and how they convey their thoughts to you. Think about the principles and values they hold and how they got to where they are. What emerges is their vision of what this country should be. Now, imagine that vision becoming reality and decide if that is the country you want to live in. Then vote.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2012/10/vision&quot;&gt;A candidate's vision&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Rob Knight at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Rob Knight&lt;/a&gt; on October 23, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Explored]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2012/10/explored" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2012/10/explored</id>
  <published>2012-10-02T11:06:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2012-10-02T11:06:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Rob Knight</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>hello@robknight.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/2012/10/flickr-home-explore.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of the flickr explore page&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/rknight/8043806400/in/photostream/&quot;&gt;sunrise photo from yesterday&lt;/a&gt; is cycling through the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/explore/&quot;&gt;Explore page on Flickr&lt;/a&gt;. Humbling and crazy. Thank you to everyone who has gone to take a look.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2012/10/explored&quot;&gt;Explored&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Rob Knight at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Rob Knight&lt;/a&gt; on October 02, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Act your age]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2012/08/act-your-age" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2012/08/act-your-age</id>
  <published>2012-08-24T12:26:57-07:00</published>
  <updated>2012-08-24T12:26:57-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Rob Knight</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>hello@robknight.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/2012/08/20120825-002824.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A couple watches the ocean at Natural Bridges State Beach&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I was thinking that I’ve lived 36 years on this planet. So, I know what it feels like to be every age from 0 to 36.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I thought about situations in life, good or bad. In any situation, I choose how to react to it. The older I get, the more choices I have. Meaning, at any given moment, I can choose to be 5 or 15 or 34 or any age in between.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I’ll be the first to say there are a lot of times when it is important and fun to be 7. I’m thinking about when the sprinklers come on (although it’s tricky now because I have to find a safe, dry place for my iPhone. I’m considering carrying a ziploc bag with me where ever I go). I’ve hardly ever met a sprinkler I didn’t want to run through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, the best way to act your age is to act another age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likewise, there are moments when I need to act every ounce of 36. Not just for my own sake, but for the sake of those who depend on me. It’s not always easy to act the right age. And being tired or stressed can make it even harder. As a situation gets more difficult, the tougher it is to act my age. I suspect I’m not alone in experiencing that. But as long as I make an effort to be calm and poised, in any situation, I figure I’ll get as close as possible to acting the right age.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2012/08/act-your-age&quot;&gt;Act your age&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Rob Knight at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Rob Knight&lt;/a&gt; on August 24, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[I made a book.]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2011/10/book" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2011/10/book</id>
  <published>2011-10-24T21:23:28-07:00</published>
  <updated>2011-10-24T21:23:28-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Rob Knight</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>hello@robknight.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blurb.com/books/2481689&quot;&gt;I made a book.&lt;/a&gt; It’s not perfect (I think the dimensions are too big), but I like it. It’s a collection of photos and writing I created between June 2010 and August 2011. It was a very tumultuous, beautiful, difficult, humbling and profoundly amazing time for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blurb.com/books/2481689&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2011/10/IMG_2325-1024x567.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My Blurb book&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book covers a very distinct chapter of my life. A period when every aspect of my life was up in the air. I accepted some of my weaknesses and made some significant changes to how I live these precious few moments of time I will be here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe that sounds a bit melancholy. But that is what motivates me. That is how I motivate myself. My time is precious because, by nature’s standards, it will be short. How short? I don’t know. I think 80-90 years sounds about right. But no one knows for sure. Everything is a river. Time is just flowing by. What am I doing to make the most of it? I don’t always know, but I’ve tried to stop letting fear or “&lt;em&gt;the way you are supposed to do things&lt;/em&gt;” get in the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past year, I became a more solid person. Solidly grounded and focused on how I can surround myself with people I love and meaningful experiences. I’ve also become more at peace with the person I am: sometimes gregarious and silly and sometimes quiet and introspective. Making that peace was a journey that at times broke me into little pieces. I’ve collected some of those pieces as well as the mementos from that journey in this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me be clear: I didn’t solve any existentialist dilemmas in my little book of corny poems and sunset photos. I simply used a couple of different forms of art (writing and photography) to document the thought processes by which I learned a little bit more about myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe there is something in this book you can relate to. That would be incredibly humbling and neat for me. If there isn’t? That’s ok too. Either way, thank you for taking a look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to buy it to see it. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blurb.com/books/2481689&quot;&gt;You can flip through it on Blurb.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2011/10/book&quot;&gt;I made a book.&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Rob Knight at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Rob Knight&lt;/a&gt; on October 24, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Natural Bridges]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2011/08/natural-bridges" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2011/08/natural-bridges</id>
  <published>2011-08-14T01:23:57-07:00</published>
  <updated>2011-08-14T01:23:57-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Rob Knight</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>hello@robknight.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I originally wrote this earlier this year. I think in February. I didn’t like it when I wrote it, but now it seems like something worth sharing. It was a very nice way to end a Friday.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last night after work, I grabbed my guitar out of the trunk of my car and walked down to Natural Bridges state beach to watch the sunset. I’ve had my guitar in my trunk for the past couple of days. I’ve stepped away from work a couple of times to walk down and play guitar on the beach for awhile. Yes, it sounds cliché and silly. And I’ll forgive you for whatever thought just crossed your mind about me potentially being a hippy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not the kind of person who is comfortable singing and playing in front of people. But with the ocean churning in the background, I’m much more at peace walking around, singing songs and clobbering my guitar strings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday nights at Natural Bridges tend to be like Friday nights at the movie theater. There were plenty of people out to watch the sun go down. Still, I was able to find myself a spot to walk around and play without interrupting anyone’s moment of natural beauty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few minutes of playing, I saw that a toddler, no more than 1-year old and wobbling around the beach with her parents, had taken an interest in me. She fearlessly started toward me, squeaking and pointing the whole way. Her parents seemed apprehensive to disturb me, so I knelt down and offered my guitar to the slowly approaching little one. She got even more excited and continued to make her way up to my guitar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her mom spoke to her in English and her dad spoke to her in French. It was very cool to watch them explain to her what it was and what she was doing in both languages. She had obviously strummed (I’m using that term loosely) a guitar before, so I held a few notes while she hit the strings. Her little face was mesmerized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a really neat moment and a perfect way to end the week. I stayed out there for another 30 minutes, playing in the dark until my fingers got so numb I had to stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the day, I had lunch with friends and we were talking about how amazingly lucky we were to live in a place as beautiful as Santa Cruz. So, after playing guitar on the beach at sunset and letting a toddler curiously strum along while her parents spoke to her in French and English, all I can do is agree. I’m pretty lucky to live and work here.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2011/08/natural-bridges&quot;&gt;Natural Bridges&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Rob Knight at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Rob Knight&lt;/a&gt; on August 14, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Right-handed thoughts]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2011/08/right-handed-thoughts" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2011/08/right-handed-thoughts</id>
  <published>2011-08-09T00:36:37-07:00</published>
  <updated>2011-08-09T00:36:37-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Rob Knight</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>hello@robknight.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, I started writing and drawing with my right hand. I’m naturally left-handed, so the result has been both child-like and comical. And the look of my right-handed penmanship has definitely influenced the subject matter of most of these drawings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, on the plane flight home from Seattle, I was thinking about more serious things and decided a right-handed drawing might be the best way to express some heavier thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally I post these on Facebook. But I think this one is better suited here, where things are more quiet. This isn’t intended to start a religious debate. These are just my thoughts, poured out at 37,000 feet, through my right hand. Cheers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/2011/08/20110809-012203.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2011/08/20110809-012203.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20110809-012203.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2011/08/right-handed-thoughts&quot;&gt;Right-handed thoughts&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Rob Knight at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Rob Knight&lt;/a&gt; on August 09, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Watch out for in your ear]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2011/05/in-your-ear" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2011/05/in-your-ear</id>
  <published>2011-05-23T21:18:09-07:00</published>
  <updated>2011-05-23T21:18:09-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Rob Knight</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>hello@robknight.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is one of my all-time favorite &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0097351/quotes?qt=qt0314985&quot;&gt;movie exchanges&lt;/a&gt;. From &lt;em&gt;Field of Dreams&lt;/em&gt;, Shoeless Joe Jackson coaches Archie Graham about what pitch to expect after the first two pitches barely miss his forehead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shoeless Joe Jackson: The first two were high and tight, so where do you think the next one’s gonna be?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Archie Graham: Well, either low and away, or &lt;em&gt;in my ear&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shoeless Joe Jackson: He’s not gonna wanna load the bases, so look low and away.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Archie Graham: Right.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shoeless Joe Jackson: But watch out for in your ear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love that he says “watch out” for in your ear. Don’t look for it. Just react if need be. If you are on the lookout for the pitch that’s headed for your skull, you’ll never &lt;a href=&quot;http://t.co/klPEiUJ&quot;&gt;hit the sweet pitch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2011/05/in-your-ear&quot;&gt;Watch out for in your ear&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Rob Knight at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Rob Knight&lt;/a&gt; on May 23, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[My new friend]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2011/05/my-new-friend" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2011/05/my-new-friend</id>
  <published>2011-05-22T21:31:33-07:00</published>
  <updated>2011-05-22T21:31:33-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Rob Knight</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>hello@robknight.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/2011/05/me-and-darcy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Darcy and I&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is Darcy. She is a 6-year old Italian Greyhound. She is tiny, bony, and shy. She is also very sweet. Yesterday, we became friends. Apparently, Darcy doesn’t make friends easy. So I feel pretty lucky that she decided I was friend material…and that my lap was a cozy place to hang out for awhile. Thanks Darcy. And thanks to Kev and Michelle for showing me around Walnut Creek.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2011/05/my-new-friend&quot;&gt;My new friend&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Rob Knight at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Rob Knight&lt;/a&gt; on May 22, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Something bigger than me]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2011/05/something-bigger-than-me" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2011/05/something-bigger-than-me</id>
  <published>2011-05-07T11:59:14-07:00</published>
  <updated>2011-05-07T11:59:14-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Rob Knight</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>hello@robknight.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Let’s say I gathered every moment when I felt fear, uncertainty or doubt and stacked them on top of each other; and then I took each moment when something breath-taking, beautiful, magical, or unexpected happened and carefully stacked each one on top of the previous stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, say, I took every post-it note, napkin, PG&amp;amp;E bill, bank statement, cereal box, candy wrapper or piece of binder paper that I’ve ever written my thoughts on and stacked them on top of the previous stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, what if I took every single moment when I felt cared for and loved by all of the amazing people I have in my life and stacked them on top of each other, on top of the previous stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, what if I took all of the roads I’ve ever been lost on, sunsets I’ve ever seen, sunrises I’ve ever been awake for, ocean waves I’ve ever paddled into, tall trees I’ve ever silently stood beside, and full moons I’ve ever surfed under and stacked them all on top of the previous stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, suppose I took all of the hopes, dreams, blank canvases, open roads, cups of tea, bowls of veggies, climbable tree branches, late night conversations, epic surf sessions, family gatherings, multi-mile hikes, lost-in-the-middle-of-who-knows-where road trips, ripe mangoes, funny t-shirts, naps, breathless moments and ear-to-ear smiles that I have yet to experience; and stacked them on top of the previous stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would I have?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d have something much, much bigger than me. I’d have the sum of many moments and not just the emotion of any single moment. I’d have a collection of magical moments that by shear weight alone smooshed the fear, uncertainty and doubt into a pancake at the bottom. Smoosh smoosh. Smoosh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I were to stare at this stack too closely, I might get lost in one piece of it and lose sight of what’s at the top; the stacked moments yet to come. They’re coming and they’re not concerned about the ones below them. &lt;strong&gt;Whatever&lt;/strong&gt; they hold, I should look forward to them and not spend too much time dwelling on the moments stacked below. Like rings in a tree, they hold you up, but remain unchanged once they’ve happened. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something bigger than me. Yeah. Much bigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was all in a dream I had, so it might not make sense.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2011/05/something-bigger-than-me&quot;&gt;Something bigger than me&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Rob Knight at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Rob Knight&lt;/a&gt; on May 07, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alternate job opportunities for RoboCop?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2011/05/alternate-job-opportunities-for-robocop" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2011/05/alternate-job-opportunities-for-robocop</id>
  <published>2011-05-04T16:44:06-07:00</published>
  <updated>2011-05-04T16:44:06-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Rob Knight</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>hello@robknight.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last night, R &amp;amp; E and I had a conversation about &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RoboCop&quot;&gt;RoboCop&lt;/a&gt;. It’s one of my all-time favorite movies. Not because of the futuristic, sci-fi robotic action; but because I laugh really hard anytime anyone repeats &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-W6cT3Tvu9g&quot;&gt;this line from the movie&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got to talking about other possible job opportunities for the police officer who became RoboCop. If I remember the plot right (no, I’m not going to spend even a nanosecond reviewing the plot of RoboCop on Wikipedia), all of officer Murphy’s limbs were damaged beyond repair and replaced with robotic parts when he became RoboCop. But, what if they had given him a choice between making him into RoboCop or just leaving him with (probably) no limbs?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn’t actually discuss the context for our reasoning. So I feel the need to say that these options &lt;strong&gt;only&lt;/strong&gt; apply to the severely injured officer Murphy of the Detroit Police Department. I think it is safe to say that the Detroit portrayed in the movie basically had three kinds of people: cops, criminals, and victims. Given that limited set of employment opportunities, we decided the injured officer Murphy’s career choices come down to the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;He decides to let the fancy doctors who cuss a lot make him into RoboCop.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;He becomes an extra in porn movies (“I’m just here to watch”).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other, less viable options such as paperweight, children’s toy, and giant drain plug were immediately dismissed or not said aloud during the discussion. As I type this, I think voice-over actor is another possibility. I remember there being a lot of television in RoboCop. So that is a viable option for a guy with the voice of officer Murphy. I bet you could make a pretty cool cartoon character with the catch phrase, “Dead or alive, you’re coming with me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there you go. Other viable career opportunities for the injured officer Murphy. We discussed this. For &lt;em&gt;awhile&lt;/em&gt;. For &lt;em&gt;far&lt;/em&gt; longer than anyone should discuss the merits of a limbless Detroit police officer acting as an extra in a porn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m so going to hell for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: corrected spelling (caps on the C) of “RoboCop”; corrected spelling of “sergeant” and then removed it because I couldn’t find proof officer Murphy was actually a sergeant.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2011/05/alternate-job-opportunities-for-robocop&quot;&gt;Alternate job opportunities for RoboCop?&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Rob Knight at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Rob Knight&lt;/a&gt; on May 04, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Betterman]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2011/05/betterman" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2011/05/betterman</id>
  <published>2011-05-02T22:05:42-07:00</published>
  <updated>2011-05-02T22:05:42-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Rob Knight</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>hello@robknight.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In November of 1994, I was busy with 4 things: going to junior college in the morning, loading boxes into trailers at UPS in the evening, and dating a pseudo-Catholic girl who had anger issues in the &lt;em&gt;later&lt;/em&gt; evening. At that age, you could basically sum up my relationship skills as “just happy to (still) be there.” I spent a fair amount of time wondering when and how I was going to get dumped. It’s funny now, to think I woke up every morning and used a few cognitive cycles wondering if that day would bring relationship carnage. But of course back then, life itself was dependent on the outcome of every phone call and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hal0gen.com/archive/anarkia/411_beeper.html&quot;&gt;pager message&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh wait, I said 4 things, didn’t I? Yeah. My buddy Jason and I spent most of the fall of 1994 waiting impatiently for the release of Pearl Jam’s third album, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vitalogy&quot;&gt;Vitalogy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m 99% sure I would have sold drugs, my body, or my little brother for a pre-release copy of Vitalogy. After all, the band had played &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8z7eZGRlKd0&quot;&gt;“Not for You” on Saturday Night Live&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;seven months&lt;/em&gt; earlier, fired their drummer over the summer, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fivehorizons.com/archive/articles/testimon.shtml&quot;&gt;started a fight with Ticketmaster&lt;/a&gt; over concert ticket service fees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This album was going to be epic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily for those of us with a crack-like addiction to PJ, Vitalogy was released on vinyl a few weeks ahead of the CD version and Jason got his hands on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vinyl is awesome, if totally non-portable. I didn’t have a record player in my 1992 VW Jetta, so I had to make a bootleg cassette tape version of Vitalogy for the car. I remember hacking together an unholy vinyl-to-tape-recorder-thing-a-ma-jiggy and, an hour later, I had my pirated cassette copy of Vitalogy (except &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Nx8lu1u1juI&quot;&gt;Stupidmop&lt;/a&gt;, because everyone skips that track anyway :-).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The song I couldn’t wait for was track 11, “&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Better_Man#Origin_and_recording&quot;&gt;Betterman&lt;/a&gt;.” It’s a somewhat sad song (hello, 90’s anti-ballad. Would you like a tissue?) about a woman who is stuck in an unhappy place; with only her dreams to comfort her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;She lies and says she still loves him.&lt;br /&gt;
Can’t find a better man.&lt;br /&gt;
She dreams in color, she dreams in red.&lt;br /&gt;
Can’t find a better man. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first week I owned my pirated cassette tape, I listened to Betterman at least 50 times. If you are under age 25, you have no idea how difficult that was. You had to &lt;strong&gt;rewind&lt;/strong&gt; the tape. And it didn’t just stop where it was supposed to. You had to &lt;em&gt;guess&lt;/em&gt; where to press the play button and hope you stopped it at the right moment. Knowing precisely where to stop the tape is truly a lost art. But I digress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few listens to Betterman, I remember wondering if my angry girlfriend was like the woman in the song. Lying about being in love (whatever “love” is at 19 years old) because she could not muster the strength to leave and find a better man. Was my girlfriend dreaming in color? In red? I could only think about one side of that song; that girl who was dreaming in color. In red.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately for me, a few months later, I came to terms with the fact that she was just angry and there was nothing I could do about it. She had a bad relationship with her dad and being angry with me was her therapy. So I moved on. And that was closest I ever got to being Catholic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last fall, Pearl Jam &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MU-dPK78U0E&quot;&gt;played a retooled and slower version of Betterman&lt;/a&gt; at Neil Young’s Bridge School benefit concert at Shoreline Amphitheater. Listen while you read on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After hearing this version of Betterman, I found the song was once again stuck in my head for a spell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My interpretation of Betterman has become less naive as I’ve gotten older. No one you love should be resigned to only &lt;em&gt;dream&lt;/em&gt; in color. I think if you’re living well, you’re in search of that color all the time. I think life is about finding the color you dream about in real life; about finding yourself a spot from which you can see all the color the world has to offer. And finding a way to add your own color to it as well. Creating your own palette and throwing brush strokes at the sky. If your dreams are more colorful than your waking hours, that might be a sign that it’s time to rattle your bones, take a deep breath, and jump.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, though, is that you allow those you love to find color in the way that best suits them. Sometimes that means letting them go seek a better place, a better life, or a better…something. Maybe that’s just for awhile. Or maybe it’s forever. The only way to be a Betterman, is to know/understand/respect when it’s time to let go. Let them go. Just let it all go and see what finds its way back to you.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2011/05/betterman&quot;&gt;Betterman&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Rob Knight at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Rob Knight&lt;/a&gt; on May 02, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magnetic North]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2011/02/magnetic-north" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2011/02/magnetic-north</id>
  <published>2011-02-22T21:45:29-08:00</published>
  <updated>2011-02-22T21:45:29-08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Rob Knight</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>hello@robknight.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are two kinds of north: geographic north and magnetic north. If you head toward geographic north, eventually, you will reach the point at the top of the earth that is furthest from the equator. It never changes. Geographic north is always in the same place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other north is magnetic north. Magnetic north is where the north pole of the earth’s invisible magnetic field is strongest. Magnetic north is more fluid. It changes location. It ebbs and flows. At various points in history, it has flipped entirely, and north became south on a compass. The exact location of magnetic north is not fixed the way geographic north is. In fact, it is currently &lt;a href=&quot;http://science.nasa.gov/science-news/science-at-nasa/2003/29dec_magneticfield/&quot;&gt;moving at a rate of 25 miles per year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use a compass to find magnetic north, but heading toward north on a compass won’t get you to geographic north unless you do some math.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most maps have a little tool printed on them called a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magnetic_declination&quot;&gt;magnetic declination&lt;/a&gt; number. That number tells you how many degrees to add or subtract from your compass reading in order to point to geographic north. In other words, if you look at your compass and head north, unless you add or subtract your declination number, you will not get to the same place that your map says is north.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such is the same with life. There’s a practical, logical way to walk through life. It is the map we draw in our heads as children. The topography of that map is shaped by our culture, environment, and the expectations of our family and friends. By the time we reach our teenage years, geographic north is established on that map and we start moving in that general direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there is what you feel in your bones. What moves you to distraction. What the artist inside you whispers in your ears while you sleep. The direction you choose based on your own internal magnetic field and the way it interacts with your surroundings. Instincts, intuition, and “gut feelings” lead you toward your magnetic north. It’s not on the map. Only your internal compass can take you there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere between the map we leave the house with and the invisible pull of magnetic north is our path in life. There is no prescription for how you align your path and toward which version of north you head. I think we all know when we’ve drifted too far off the path toward geographic north. Likewise, we know not to ignore the pull of magnetic north, where ever it may be at any given moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I think that is the secret: &lt;em&gt;accepting&lt;/em&gt; that you need a compass &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; a map on this journey. Sometimes, you follow the map and sometimes you put it away and let the compass tell you which direction to travel. You carefully protect both, but don’t ignore the importance of either the map or the compass.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2011/02/magnetic-north&quot;&gt;Magnetic North&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Rob Knight at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Rob Knight&lt;/a&gt; on February 22, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Liftoff]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2011/01/liftoff" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2011/01/liftoff</id>
  <published>2011-01-01T14:46:38-08:00</published>
  <updated>2011-01-01T14:46:38-08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Rob Knight</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>hello@robknight.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2011/01/salton_sea_balloon-560x373.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hot air balloon over Mecca, California&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some years come and go and fade from memory as if they were only seconds long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2010 was not one of those years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2010 was one of those years that will get it’s own rest stop on this journey. A place to both lose AND catch my breathe while recalling moments from the last 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I experienced some of the most difficult moments of my life in 2010, I also experienced some of the most amazing moments of my life. Sometimes both in the same day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And through it all, life is beautiful. Beautiful. And special. And I am fortunate for all things in my life. Good and bad. And I’m doubly fortunate to have so many amazing people to share these things with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2010, I learned to live differently. To love differently. To enjoy these moments I have here with you all. Because they are all precious. And we all don’t get the same number of moments to share together. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2010, I decided to try to stop using the word impossible. Because anything is possible. I traveled more in 2010 than I would have ever thought possible. I ended the year by spending Christmas in Seattle with my extended family for the first time ever. Then I flew to southern California and fulfilled a 10-year old dream of seeing the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.desertusa.com/video_pages/salton-sea.html&quot;&gt;Salton Sea&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And even though I’m sitting here on the first day of 2011 with a fever, chills, and the worst cold I’ve had in years, I’m looking forward to all of the possibilities and magic we will all create in 2011. Happy new year, everyone. Let’s play.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2011/01/liftoff&quot;&gt;Liftoff&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Rob Knight at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Rob Knight&lt;/a&gt; on January 01, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[witness]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2010/12/witness" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2010/12/witness</id>
  <published>2010-12-14T01:03:29-08:00</published>
  <updated>2010-12-14T01:03:29-08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Rob Knight</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>hello@robknight.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I took a different route home from work tonight. I decided not to try highway 1 and instead took city streets. I was going to take Water Street, but decided Soquel Avenue would be quicker. As I came down Capitola Road toward 30th Avenue, I noticed a woman and a man crossing the street. Beside the fact that they were 30 feet outside of a nearby crosswalk, there was something weird about the way they were moving. I got a sense she was trying to avoid him. Maybe he was chasing her? She crossed over to my side of the street and he was still in my lane, but several hundred feet in front of me. He was easily going to get to the sidewalk before I drove by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the woman darted back across the street to the opposite side of the road. The man seemed to hesitate in the middle of the road for a second and then turn around and start back after her. There was a strange look about both of them that kept me watching them. I couldn’t figure out what they were doing or why they were so erratic in their movements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched him closely as he started to make his way back to the side of the road where they started. He seemed to hesitate before making one last quick move toward the sidewalk where the woman was standing–now with a cell phone to her ear. And then I watched as he was struck and flung into the air by a black car that had just left the green light at the nearby intersection. The sound was awful. I heard it through my closed windows. I watched the victim’s body spin–end over end–and crash to the pavement. I can still see it when I close my eyes. I wish I couldn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pulled over and was on my phone dialing 911 within 10 seconds. I waited for all of the traffic to pass before getting out of the van to make my way to the scene. I gave all of the information I could to the 911 operator. As I walked up to the man, now on his back on the sidewalk, I assumed he had likely been killed by the impact with the car. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was breathing, but it was labored and heavy. He was unconscious, and his body was clearly fighting to keep itself going. He was being attended to by an off-duty firefighter who happened to drive by. It was hard to watch. A few seconds before, this man was the crazy guy in the street. Now I might be witnessing his last moments of life. I asked the firefighter if there was anything I could do, but he said paramedics were on the way and it was best to keep my distance. In the small crowd that had gathered near the victim, I recognized the woman who had been in the road with him. I tried to speak to her, but she did not speak English and began crying when my first question (“Was he chasing you?”) was translated to her by another family member. I didn’t feel right bothering her anymore. The family member who translated my question said she was the victim’s wife. I stepped back a few feet and stood there quietly. Why they were in the road didn’t matter any more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another woman approached me and asked if I saw the incident. I told her I did and that I had called 911 immediately. “So you saw everything?” she asked. It was the way she asked that made me feel somewhat strange. “So you saw that he came out of nowhere? We didn’t even see him.” She was the passenger in the car that struck the man. I told her I saw the man dart across the street erratically and that I saw their car strike him. She asked me to stay and talk with the CHP officer, which I had planned to do anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After giving my statement to the CHP officer, I learned that I was the only witness who saw the whole incident. Others may have witnessed the incident, but no one else stopped to give their accounts. I hope someone else will come forward to describe what they saw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was on the scene for another few minutes before being excused by the CHP officer who took my statement. I shook the hand of the man who was driving the car that struck the victim and told him I hoped he was ok. He thanked me for stopping and giving my statement. Then, with tears in his eyes, he wished me a Merry Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked by the family of the victim and told them I hoped he would be ok. I didn’t know what else to say. We had all watched the same scene. It didn’t look good. I can still see it. I wish I couldn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be careful. Be kind to your neighbors. Drive safe.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2010/12/witness&quot;&gt;witness&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Rob Knight at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Rob Knight&lt;/a&gt; on December 14, 2010.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[We try]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2010/11/we-try" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2010/11/we-try</id>
  <published>2010-11-09T00:50:05-08:00</published>
  <updated>2010-11-09T00:50:05-08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Rob Knight</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>hello@robknight.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/rknight/5156782095/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4071/5156782095_c895acbd51_b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16 sunsets from highway 101, north of King City, Ca&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyday  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We try to learn.&lt;br /&gt;
We try to teach.&lt;br /&gt;
We try to keep smiles within our reach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We try to be stronger.&lt;br /&gt;
Do things that scare us.&lt;br /&gt;
Stand up tall when life dares us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We laugh as much as we can.&lt;br /&gt;
Sometimes, we cry.&lt;br /&gt;
We try to be angels in our mother’s eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We try not to be hurt by what others might say.&lt;br /&gt;
We share our love to keep our fears at bay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look for the moment-of-truth&lt;br /&gt;
under the rocks we skipped over the previous day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look at the sky as we cover one eye&lt;br /&gt;
and we see dragons and lion manes and far off places like&lt;br /&gt;
forests where nature and magic play&lt;br /&gt;
side by side, intertwined&lt;br /&gt;
just like in our minds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then the sun sets&lt;br /&gt;
and we try to get some rest&lt;br /&gt;
and our heads keep spinning&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KP2Wlp4mabo&quot;&gt;playful, gentle spinning&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We dream sweet dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll try everything again tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if the sun should not rise&lt;br /&gt;
for all of us&lt;br /&gt;
the next day&lt;br /&gt;
we’ll know we lived our fullest,&lt;br /&gt;
shared our love with them,&lt;br /&gt;
every moment of this day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can’t be taken away.&lt;br /&gt;
This day.&lt;br /&gt;
And &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; day we try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written for my cousin Jody, who passed away at age 39 on Sunday, November 7, 2010 after a courageous bout with cancer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2010/11/we-try&quot;&gt;We try&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Rob Knight at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Rob Knight&lt;/a&gt; on November 09, 2010.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[My left shoulder]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2010/09/my-left-shoulder" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2010/09/my-left-shoulder</id>
  <published>2010-09-03T20:36:03-07:00</published>
  <updated>2010-09-03T20:36:03-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Rob Knight</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>hello@robknight.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My left shoulder was x-rayed on Tuesday. Everything is mostly OK. Just have to take it easy for awhile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/2010/09/my-left-shoulder.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My left shoulder x-ray&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2010/09/my-left-shoulder&quot;&gt;My left shoulder&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Rob Knight at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Rob Knight&lt;/a&gt; on September 03, 2010.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[magic.]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2010/08/magic" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2010/08/magic</id>
  <published>2010-08-12T02:27:26-07:00</published>
  <updated>2010-08-12T02:27:26-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Rob Knight</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>hello@robknight.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/rknight/4885001580/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm5.staticflickr.com/4079/4885001580_3cce4d39b0_b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sunset at UCSC&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was 7 years old, &lt;em&gt;magic&lt;/em&gt; was something a birthday party magician performed when he put a rabbit in a metal container, waved a wand over it, and turned it into a bowl of milk (that actually happened). And even though I’ve often wondered what became of that rabbit, I remember being amazed by the &lt;em&gt;magic&lt;/em&gt; I thought that magician-for-hire had harnessed. He could turn a rabbit into milk!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several years later, I remember thinking David Copperfield performed magic when he made the Statue of Liberty disappear with nothing more than an expensive hair cut, a series of strange hip gyrations, and some melodramatic hand movements. Poof. Magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I’m old enough to know that drowning a rabbit in milk (not confirmed, but suspected) is not magic. And choreographed pelvic thrusts cannot make the Statue of Liberty disappear. But that doesn’t mean there is no such thing as magic. There is &lt;em&gt;totally&lt;/em&gt; magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, I took a walk to the beach after work. I put my hands in the water and let a few waves wash over them. They had a little bit of blood on them from a cut, and admittedly, a few dried tears from more than one conversation I’d had during the day. I closed my eyes and imagined the difficult parts of my day being carried out to sea. Gone forever. I bet they sank. Like magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to magic, Nature can bring it. Sunsets are magic and we see them every day. Have you ever seen a sunset that wasn’t magic? Every sunset I’ve ever seen has been magic in a different way. Every wave I’ve ever caught on my surfboard has been magic. Though I will admit, winter waves can feel more like a magic washing machine if you don’t watch yourself. Still, a good ride is magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of magic in human interactions. When I was a kid, I was shy and afraid to look people in the eyes. I’ve worked hard to overcome that fear because there is always a chance for magic when you look someone in the eye. Friendship, an unexpected laugh, a moment of understanding…are all little bits of magic. When you do something unexpected for someone, that is magical for that person. They didn’t even see it coming and like magic, their day is improved. That is kick-ass magic. The magical people I know are so good at spotting or creating magic that it makes them exciting to be around. They help remind us all that magic exists everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, this all sounds kind of cheesy, I know. But, I think we make our own magic. And there is no age limit. Magic is not what you see, it is &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; you see. Kids see a lot of magic because they don’t have as many answers to life’s questions. We can &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; see more magic if we choose to look for it. Or close our eyes and imagine it. Or make magic for others. One way or another, it’s out there.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2010/08/magic&quot;&gt;magic.&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Rob Knight at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Rob Knight&lt;/a&gt; on August 12, 2010.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[I don't know what I'm doing.]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2010/08/i-dont-know-what-im-doing" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2010/08/i-dont-know-what-im-doing</id>
  <published>2010-08-07T23:06:36-07:00</published>
  <updated>2010-08-07T23:06:36-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Rob Knight</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>hello@robknight.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last Fall, I &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/robknight/status/4348529477&quot;&gt;posted a tweet&lt;/a&gt; that simply said, “I don’t know what I’m doing.” At the time, I really didn’t know what I was doing. A lot of thoughts were spinning around in my head and a general feeling of uneasiness dominated my mindset. It was a weird time that I ended up pondering in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://robknight.net/2009/11/intentionally-left-blank&quot;&gt;couple&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;http://robknight.net/2009/11/dumb-thing&quot;&gt;posts&lt;/a&gt; I wrote late last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As short-lived as tweets are, I’ve remembered that line several times recently. I’ve said it quietly to myself. I’ve written down on sticky notes and stuck it to the side of my monitor. I started to write it on my hand in pen one day before realizing that might be difficult to explain to others. Not knowing what you are doing is one thing. Going bat-shit crazy and writing phrases on your hand makes the neighbors look at you funny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/robknight/status/4348529477&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/2010/08/tweet.png&quot; alt=&quot;I don't know what I'm doing by Rob Knight on Twitter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, rather than invoke fear or concern, I’ve come to love that phrase. When I say it to myself, it makes me smile. When I see it, I see something completely different than I saw last Fall. Even though that sentiment is more true now than at any other time in my life, it brings me a small level of comfort that I appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know what I’m doing. I really don’t. And that’s the beauty of it all. If I did know what I was doing, everything would be too easy. Life would be easy. And probably pretty boring. If I don’t know what I’m doing, I’m probably being creatively challenged to come up with answers to some difficult problems. Or I’m dealing with life situations that I’ve never dealt with before. Or I’m trying to shed worries and fears that kept me from achieving my goals. That is far more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was having a conversation with a friend on Friday and we were talking about LOST. I was talking about how the end of the show left a lot of unanswered questions. I wasn’t concerned that I didn’t get all of my questions answered. There were plenty of questions I didn’t want answers to. There is such a beauty in not knowing how things are going to turn out. Part of that beauty is you get to shape it and it will invariably twist and turn and surprise you. It’s a risk, right? A beautiful risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, you just have to do what you feel is the best thing to do at a particular moment and then see what happens. Because feelings…nope. Not going to say it. Just can’t say it. (Sorry, inside joke. Ask me about it in person)&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2010/08/i-dont-know-what-im-doing&quot;&gt;I don't know what I'm doing.&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Rob Knight at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Rob Knight&lt;/a&gt; on August 07, 2010.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>